## Jaden Stittsworth

Pittsburgh, PA | LinkedIn | Portfolio | 412-527-4078 | Jadenrs10@gmail.com

### **Summary**

Based in Pittsburgh, PA, I am a Full-Stack Developer with a keen expertise in the Spring Ecosystem. As a seasoned Software Tester and Developer, my proficiency spans Java, .Net, C#, and Spring. My strong testing background combined with my development skills positions me uniquely for roles that require a deep understanding of both testing and full-stack development.

### WORK EXPERIENCE

Talogy Tech - FTE Pittsburgh, PA

Software Developer in Test

Nov 2022 - Present

- Implemented refactoring techniques on the existing test automation suite, improving code maintainability by 30%.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to identify and prioritize critical test cases for inclusion in the automation suite, resulting in a 20% increase in overall test coverage.
- Engaged in a dedicated self-study of C#, Azure CloudServices, ASP.NET, and Angular to deepen my knowledge and improve my proficiency in application testing, enhancing my ability to deliver high-quality results.
- Worked closely with developers to create automated tests for new features, resulting in a 50% reduction in manual testing efforts and faster time-to-market.

### Tata Consultant Agency (PNC Bank)-FTE

Pittsburgh, PA

Software Developer/Lead Test-Analyst

May 2021 - Nov 2022

- Developing & maintaining software tools used by over 50 QA Engineers, allowing them to access, reserve, and manipulate test data.
- Implemented automated testing framework utilizing Selenium and JUnit to streamline testing processes, reducing testing time by 40% and improving test coverage by 25%.
- Developed robust Spring MVC application, leveraging agile methodologies, resulting in a 15% increase in development efficiency and a 10% reduction in time-to-market. Conducted comprehensive test planning and execution for two major projects, resulting in a 30% decrease in overall defects and a 20% improvement in application performance.
- Leading the Testing efforts of a team of 5 developers responsible for testing products before release.
- Successfully migrated product from Kanban to Agile methodology, ensuring a smooth transition and no loss in productivity.
- Collaborating with the Product team to understand requirements & develop tools, which is increasing productivity by 15% and growing.
- Participated in Sprint Planning, Review Sessions,s and Scrum Meetings to provide input on achievable deliverables for each sprint.
- Utilized Jenkins to automate the execution of Smoke Tests several times a day, confirming essential functionalities worked as expected.

### **EDUCATION**

**Cydeo** *Java Full-stack developer training* 

Pittsburgh, PA Jul 2023 - present

Java Full-stack developer training **Cvdeo** 

Pittsburgh, PA

Software Development Engineer in Test BootCamp

Dec 2019 - May 2020

• Java Full Stack automation developer(SDET) program. Focused on training IT professionals from the ground up. Started basics of Java to Selenium to SQL and on. This program produces some of the sharpest Test Automation Engineers in the market.

# Mt. Lebanon High School

Pittsburgh, PA

High School Diploma

2016 - 2019

• Was extremely passionate about my AP Computer Science and CISCO classes. Knew very early on this would be my career. Mt. Lebanon provided an unmatched education that prepared me to start my journey as early as possible. Was able to graduate early and begin my work in my boot camp.

#### **SKILLS & INTERESTS**

**Skills:** Java, .Net, C#, JavaScript | HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Tailwind, Next.JS, React | Selenium, Cucumber, Karate, Appium, JUnit, TestNG, RestAssured | SQL JDBC R2DBC | Jenkins Git Azure | Excel Jira | Postman Docker | Spring Ecosystem